[
  {
    "question": "In a mortgage loan, what portion constitutes a <strong>bonus</strong>?",
    "answer": "The bonus is the portion of the face value of a mortgage loan which exceeds the funds actually received by the borrower and which is intended as additional compensation for the lender."
  },
  {
    "question": "A <strong>closed mortgage</strong> is a mortgage which _______ be fully paid out before _______ of its term.",
    "answer": "A closed mortgage is a mortgage which <strong>cannot</strong> be fully paid out before <strong>expiry</strong> of its term."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define the <strong>cost of funds advanced to the borrower</strong>.",
    "answer": "The cost of funds advanced to the borrower is the rate of interest charged on the mortgage loan amount after all fees and bonuses are deducted."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define <strong>prepayment penalties</strong>.",
    "answer": "In a closed mortgage, a lender who allows the borrower to prepay part of the outstanding balance will charge a prepayment penalty. The penalty will be the greater of three months' interest or the interest rate differential on the amount to be prepaid."
  },
  {
    "question": "Define a <strong>vendor take-back mortgage</strong>.",
    "answer": "A vendor take-back mortgage is one in which the vendor acts as a lender to the purchaser. The financing provided on a vendor take-back mortgage is usually offered at a rate below the current market rate."
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the purpose of a <strong>portable mortgage</strong>.",
    "answer": "A portable mortgage gives the borrower the flexibility to sell one home and purchase another before the current mortgage matures. The borrower may transfer the terms, conditions and interest rate from one home to another."
  },
  {
    "question": "Where an offer to purchase involves financing below the market rate of interest, the market value of the offer will be worth ______ than the stated offer price.",
    "answer": "Where an offer to purchase involves financing below the market rate of interest, the market value of the offer will be worth <strong>less</strong> than the stated offer price."
  },
  {
    "question": "Mortgage assumption is more common during times of rising interest rates because established low rates are attractive.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "Mortgage assumption is more common during times of rising interest rates because established low rates are attractive.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  },
  {
    "question": "In BC, mortgage lenders and brokers must satisfy the requirements of the _______ _______ ____ ________ _______ _____ by disclosing to the borrower the _______ ________ ______.",
    "answer": "In BC, mortgage lenders and brokers must satisfy the requirements of the <strong>Business Practices and Consumer Protection Act</strong> (BPCPA) by disclosing to the borrower the <strong>Annual Percentage Rate</strong> (APR)."
  },
  {
    "question": "In a closed mortgage with a term under 5 years, there is no legal obligation on the part of the lender to allow <strong>total repayment</strong> during the duration of the term.<br />&nbsp;(1) True<br />&nbsp;(2) False",
    "answer": "In a closed mortgage with a term under 5 years, there is no legal obligation on the part of the lender to allow <strong>total repayment</strong> during the duration of the term.<br />&nbsp;<strong>(1) True</strong><br />&nbsp;(2) False"
  }
]